Guide to the Hayes Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Hayes Family Papers
1888-2005
RG 18
Yale University Divinity School Library
23
(59 boxes)
These papers provide detailed accounts of the life and work of the Hayes family in China during a turbulent time, as well as documenting their post-China experiences. Paul and Helen Wolf Hayes were missionaries serving under the Methodist Episcopal Church in Wuhu and Chinkiang, Anhwei Province from 1921 to 1935. Following their return to the United States, Paul Hayes had pastorates in Minnesota and North Dakota. Their daughter, Elsie Hayes Landstrom, was born in China; she wrote and edited various works related to the work of her parents and other Methodist missionaries.
Hayes, Paul G.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Elsie Hayes Landstrom and Lois Hayes Anderson, 1987.
Biographical / Historical
Chronology of Paul G. Hayes
1890 Sep 1 Born at 558 N. Queen Street, Lancaster, PA. Son of Zachariah T. Hayes (1849 Sep 17-1901 Apr 1) and Emma Amelia (Goodman) Hayes (1857 Mar 17-1919 Oct 23). One sister, Rhoda Amelia Hayes (1892 Sep 7-1973 Sep 25, never married)
1904-1910 Dropped out of public school to help support mother and sister. Worked as office boy, then bookkeeper, Lebzelter Bending Works, Lancaster, PA
1907 First attended the Gospel Mission in Lancaster (predecessor to Union Gospel Mission and Water St. Mission); made decision to dedicate his life to Christ
1910-1911 Union Missionary Training Institute, Brooklyn, NY
1911-1913 Franklin Marshall Academy, Lancaster, PA
1913-1917 Franklin Marshall College, Lancaster, PA: B.A., Phi Beta Kappa, Marshall oration (highest honor)
1915-1917 Superintendent, Water Street Mission, Lancaster (reorganized, with others, 1915; started rescue services with Herman Molin, 1917)
1916-1917 Student pastor, Ross Street Methodist Church, Lancaster (founded, with others, 1916)
1917Sep 8 Married Mary Elizabeth Zwally (died 1918, 'flu epidemic)
1917-1918 Student Pastor, Linden Methodist Church, Malden, MA
1917-1920 Boston University School of Theology, S.T.B.
1919-1920 Student Pastor, Fremont Congregational Church, Fremont, NH
1920-1921 B.U.S.T. graduate studies toward Ph D.
1921 Aug 10 Sailed for China on the Korea Maru from San Francisco, under the auspices of the Board of Missions of the Methodist Episcopal Church. Met Helen Mae Wolf, Reformed Church missionary, aboard ship
1921-1922 Nanking Language School at the University of Nanking
1922 Jun 13 Married Helen Mae Wolf (1896 Nov 8-1988 Jul 19). Children: Elsie Rhoda, born 1923 Jun 22 at Kuling, on Lushan, Kiangsi, China and Lois Anne, born 1931 Nov 8 at Wuhu, China.
1921-1926 First term in Wuhu, Anhwei, China
1926-1928 Furlough
1926 Union Theological Seminary grad. studies
1927 Hartford Seminary Foundation, cont. studies toward Ph.D.; completed all but dissertation; took materials to China to write dissertation, but never had the time. Summer pastor at Clinton (CT) Methodist Episcopal Church
1927-28 Served at Grace Methodist Episcopal Church, Windsor Locks, CT
1929-1935 Second Term in China
1929-30 in Chinkiang
1930-35 in Wuhu
1935-1936 Associate Pastor, Simpson Methodist Church, Minneapolis, MN
1936-1941 Pastor, Calvary Methodist Church, Minneapolis, MN
1941-1949 Pastor, McCabe Methodist Church, Bismarck, ND; Member Board of Ministerial Training, Board of Missions, North Dakota Conference, Dean Summer School Ministerial Training, 1947, 1948
1949 Honorary Doctor of Divinity, University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, with which Wesley College, Fargo, affiliated
1949-1955 Pastor, First Methodist Church, Albert Lea, MN
1955-1961 District Superintendent, Minnesota Southeast District
1955-1966 Directorates of Rochester Methodist Hospital, Rochester, MN; Paul Watkins Memorial Methodist Home, Winona, MN (founded, with others, 1958); Old Frontenac Point Camp, Frontenac, MN; Fellowship Methodist Church, Austin, MN (founded, with others, 1958); Methodist Hospital, Minneapolis (1963-1966)
1961-1970 Associate Pastor, Lake Harriet Methodist Church, Minnneapolis
1970-1977 Associate Pastor, Hamline United Methodist Church, St. Paul, MN. Retired to work on memoirs (1977)
1987 Feb 11 Entered Walker Methodist Residence Health Care Center
1994Mar 1 Died at Walker Methodist Health Care Center
Consolidated from a chronology compiled by Elsie H. Landstrom, 1987 Oct 30. (See: Box 33, Folder 429)
Chronology of Helen Wolf Hayes
1896 Nov 8 Born in Bethlehem, PA. Seventh of fourteen children of Samuel Fackenthal and Ida (Bryan) Wolf.
1920-1921 Missionary training courses at Hartford Seminary Foundation Lehigh University Extension Courses; taught public school in Nazareth, PA
1921 Helen Mae Wolf Missionary Society was formed to support her work in China through the efforts of friends in the St. Andrews Reformed Church in Allentown, PA, where Helen was an active member
1921 Aug 10 Sailed for China on Korea Maru from San Francisco, under auspices of the Board of Missions of the Reformed Church in the U.S. Met Paul G. Hayes, Methodist missionary, aboard ship.
1922 Jun 13 Married Paul G. Hayes (1890 Sep 1-1994 Mar 1). Children: Elsie Rhoda, born 1923 Jun 22 at Kuling, on Lushan, Kiangsi, China and Lois Anne, born 1931 Nov 8 at Wuhu, China.
1922 Transferred to Board of Missions of the Methodist Episcopal Church
1921-1926 First term in Wuhu, Anhwei, China
1921-22 Studied Chinese at Nanking Language School, University of Nanking
1926-1928 Furlough
1926-27 Studied at Columbia University Teachers' College
1927-28 Studied at Hartford Seminary Foundation
1929-1935 Second Term in China: In China, Helen taught English in the Wuhu Primary School for one year, in the Chinkiang Girls High School for one year and in the Wuhu General Hospital School of Nursing for several years. She held teas and Bible study classes for groups of local women, and conducted a small school for missionary children in her home using the Calvert system for six years. She served as Adviser to the interdenominational Women's Club of Wuhu and helped them open an orphanage, The Hole in The Wall, for girl babies of poor families who otherwise would have been allowed to die.
1929-30 in Chinkiang
1930-35 in Wuhu
1935-1941 Northern Minnesota Conference
1935-36 Simpson Methodist Church, Minneapolis
1936-41 Calvary Methodist Church, Minneapolis
1941-1949 North Dakota Conference
1941-49 McCabe Methodist Church, Bismarck
1949-1961 Minnesota Southeast Conference
1949-55 First Methodist Church, Albert Lea
1955-61 Southeast District, based in Rochester
1961-1970 Lake Harriet Methodist Church, Minneapolis
1970-1977 Hamline United Methodist Church, St. Paul: In these Conferences of the Methodist Church, where Paul held a number of pastorates, Helen played an active role in his ministry and church life. She entertained in their home, sang in the choir, did youth work, taught church school and gave talks on China. She held leadership positions in the Minneapolis Branch of the Woman's Foreign Missionary Society, Women's Society of Christian Service, United Church Women and in the PEO and DAR. She served as Secretary of Missionary Projects and of Spiritual Life.
1987 Feb 11 Entered Walker Methodist Residence Health Care Center
1988Jul 18 Died at the Walker Residence, Minneapolis, MN
Chronology of Elsie Hayes Landstrom
1923Jun 22 Born at Kuling, on Lushan, Kiangsi, China, first daughter of Paul G. and Helen Wolf Hayes
1923-1935 Spent first 12 years of life in China; tutored at home by mother according to the Calvert plan
1935-1941 Attended public schools in Minneapolis, MN; 1941 honors graduate of North High School
1941-1945 Attended Hamline University, St. Paul, MN as Drew Scholar. B.A., magna cum laude, 1941. English teaching major, Social Science Psychology minors
1945 Jun 16 Married Harry V. Hines (divorced 1951)
1945-1946 Worked in publications research and production at a research bureau in Philadelphia, and briefly on a dictionary compiled at the University of Pennsylvania
1946-1952 Writer/editor for American Friends Service Committee (Quaker relief and service agency) in Philadelphia
1952-1953 Writer/editor of non-technical materials for Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Lincoln Laboratory
1953 Jan 21 Married Norman Landstrom (1913 Dec 8-1989 Oct 17), attorney. Children: Peter S. (born 1954 Apr 21) and Ruth H. (born 1956 Nov 7)
1953-1976 Continued writing on a volunteer basis, while devoting the majority of her time to her family. Her projects included writing a monthly newsletter for 7 years, writing and publishing about 50 poems, and providing editorial assistance to others. She taught "First Day School" in the Wellesley Friends Meeting and was a member of the Wider Quaker Fellowship and the Friends Committee on Religion and Psychology. She designed and supervised the building of their home in Conway, MA
1976-1980 Senior Editor, The Word Guild, Inc.
1981-1991 Devoted time to many writing projects, including editing the memoirs of her father and Dr. Hyla Watters
Scope and Contents
These papers, dating from 1888 to 1994, provide vivid accounts of the missionary experiences of Paul and Helen Hayes (1921-1935), details of Paul's ministry after returning to the United States, and their family and social lives. Paul and Helen met, as they often quipped, "on a slow boat to China." Although sent under the auspices of different boards, their mutual devotion to mission work, shared theological ideals, and sheer enjoyment of each other's company cemented their relationship. They studied together at the University of Nanking Department of Missionary Training, dated frequently, and corresponded much while apart. After deciding to unite in marriage, Helen realized that she must transfer her affiliation from the Reformed Church Foreign Mission Board to the Methodist Episcopal Church Foreign Mission Board so that she could serve with her husband. Since the Methodist Board was obligated to pay the costs incurred by the Reformed Board for her service, Helen often teased Paul that she had been "bought and paid for like a Chinese bride." Due to the Depression in the United States, the Methodist Board could no longer support the Hayes' missionary work in China. They were asked to return to the States in 1935 and serve in the Methodist Church, first in Minneapolis, followed by an appointment in North Dakota, and back to Minnesota where they remained for the rest of their lives. Paul "retired" three times, but essentially continued to minister in various capacities until the disabilities associated with advancing age made it impossible.
The CORRESPONDENCE of Series I is valuable for its great detail and completeness. Arranged by main correspondent, the sections are divided by family and general letters. Letters sent by Paul and Helen to their families back home document their voyage to China, experiences with Chinese life, language and customs, their friendship, courtship and subsequent marriage and family life. Letters exchanged between Paul and Helen during their courtship and marriage reveal their deep affection for each other, which endured faithfully through sixty-six years of married life. Weekly correspondence with their adult daughters serves as a dialogue on family matters, ministry, social and political concerns, reminiscences of the past and plans for the future. Both Paul and Helen were attentive to detail in their writing, so their correspondence serves as the most complete record of their missionary service, ministry, and personal lives.
Paul's general correspondence constitutes his self-titled "Journal", consisting of copies of all the letters he sent and received every year from his youth to his death. The letters reveal his stance as a social and peace activist, and include correspondence with organizations to which he offered moral support and financial assistance. He corresponded with such political figures as Presidents Kennedy, Carter, and Reagan, Senators Eugene McCarthy, Hubert Humphrey, Alan Cranston, Edward Kennedy, Wendall Anderson, Walter Mondale, and Rudy Boschwitz, Representative Donald Fraser, and Congressman Martin Sabo. He did not hesitate to give credit where credit was due, or express displeasure over their decisions with which he disagreed. He supported such causes as world hunger, disaster relief, human rights, nuclear disarmament, handgun control, the Democratic Party, the Black Panther Party and gay/lesbian rights in the church. He opposed capital punishment, abortion, drug, alcohol and tobacco use, and mandatory retirement.
Series II, BIOGRAPHICAL DOCUMENTATION, provides a subject-oriented approach to researching the Hayes family. Preserving his original arrangement, the series documents schools attended, mission work, churches served, places lived, trips/vacations taken, and special interests of Paul G. Hayes. While less material is available for Helen Hayes, her Midwest China Oral History Transcript provides valuable insight into her perspective of their China missionary experiences.
Paul Hayes' memoirs are a special attraction of the WRITINGS of Series III. Elsie Hayes Landstrom encouraged him to record these valuable memories and edited the manuscript extensively. It is a very valuable documentary of Paul's entire life. Also of interest are Paul's manuscript sermons, dating from 1907 to 1935 and 1961 to 1983.
Elsie also encouraged her mother to compile her memoirs, but this proved to be a difficult task for Helen, who was busy with duties at home and church and in declining health. Two notebooks, partially filled with her reminiscences, complement her husband's memoirs.
Elsie's talent for writing was discovered at an early age. Although she wrote for pleasure and profit throughout her life, her writings in this series constitute a sampling of her projects dating 1981-1991. They include the memoirs of Dr. Hyla Watters, which she edited, a story of the Hayes family in China, and an account of her return to the place of her birth in China.
Of interest among the family's collected items in Series IV, PERSONAL ITEMS AND MEMORABILIA, are Paul's glass slides of China, Helen's notes for talks she gave on China, and some of Elsie's collected research materials on Wuhu, China.
The photographs in Series V are largely identified.
The Hayes Family Papers are a valuable addition to the China Records Project at the Yale Divinity School Library. They complement other collections of China missionaries, particularly the papers of Albert and Celia Steward (RG 20), with whom they served in China from 1921-1935 and remained lifelong friends.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1918-1991, n.d.
II. Biographical Documentation, 1898-1994
III. Writings, 1907-1991
IV. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1888-1981
V. Photograph Albums, 1890-1949
Missions -- China; Missionaries; Hayes, Helen Wolf; Hayes, Paul G.; Landstrom, Elsie H.; Methodist Episcopal Church -- Missions -- China
- Correspondence, 1918-1991, n.d.; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence in this series is arranged as follows:
  Helen Wolf Hayes
  Family correspondence (1921-1930)
  General correspondence (1921-1932, n.d.)
  Paul G. Hayes
  Family correspondence (1918-1991, n.d.)
  General correspondence/Journal of PGH (1890-1993)
  Elsie Hayes Landstrom
  Family correspondence (1978-1987)
  General correspondence (1985-1989)
  Lois Anne Hayes Anderson
  Family correspondence (1975-1986)
  - Correspondence of Helen Wolf Hayes
    - Family Corresplondence
      - From Ida B. Wolf, mother, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - To/from Samuel Fackenthal Wolf, father, 1923, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - From Clara Wolf, younger sister, 1921, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - To/from Elsie Wolf Johnson, older sister, 1921, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - From Hannah Johnson Hennerly, niece (sister Elsie's daughter), 1930 Jun
      - From Fred Wolf, brother, 1929 Nov (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - From Paul Wolf, brother, 1929 Nov, 1930 Jan (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - To Rollin Wolf, brother, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - From Samuel Wolf, younger brother, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence
      - Board of Foreign Missions, Reformed Church in the United States, 1922 Jan (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous - A, 1921, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous - D, F, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous - H, I, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous - K, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous - M, N, O, P, 1921, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous - R, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous - S, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous - U, W, 1921-1922, 1929, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Miscellaneous - first names only, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous - group letters (incl. from friends at Kennedy School of Missions), 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence of Paul G. Hayes
    - Family Correspondence
      - To/from Emma A. Hayes, mother, 1918 Oct-1919 Mar (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - From Rhoda Hayes, sister (incl. re. illness and death of mother, 1919 Sep-Oct), 1918-1920, 1929, 1932, 1934, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
      - To/from Helen Wolf Hayes, wife, 1921-1931 (Box 2, Folder 23-36)
      - To/from Helen Wolf Hayes, wife, 1932-1961, 1972, 1976, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 37-52)
      - To/from Elsie Rhoda and Lois Anne Hayes, daughters (childhood letters), 1930-1934, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - PGH HWH to Elsie R. Hayes Landstrom and Lois Anne Hayes Anderson, daughters (see also: "Journal" of PGH for additional correspondence), 1971, 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 54-77)
      - PGH HWH to Elsie R. Hayes Landstrom and Lois Anne Hayes Anderson, daughters, 1981-1988 (Box 5, Folder 78-106)
      - PGH HWH to/from Peter Landstrom, grandson, 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 107)
      - PGH HWH to/from Ruth Landstrom Weber, granddaughter, 1970-1984 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      - PGH HWH to/from Catherine Anderson Sullivan, granddaughter, 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - PGH HWH to/from Lori Anderson Stephens, granddaughter, 1977-1986 (Box 6, Folder 110)
      - PGH HWH to/from Julie Anderson Murray, granddaughter, 1977-1987 (Box 6, Folder 111)
      - To grandchildren, 1990 Sep, 1991 Apr (Box 6, Folder 112)
      - PGH HWH: "Round Robin" letters to family, 1931-1932, 1945-1946, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 113)
      - Christmas letters to family friends, 1960-1978, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - General Correspondence/Journal
      - "Journal" of PGH; Diary, "Year by Year Notes on Personal Experiences and Family Events", 1890-1912 (Box 7, Folder 115)
      - "Journal" of PGH / "A Line A Day" diaries, 1906-1910, 1911-1915, 1916-1920, 1921-1925 (Box 7, Folder 116-117)
      - "Journal" of PGH / 6 bound diaries, typewritten, 1923 Jun 1-1931 Jun 1 (Box 8, Folder 118)
      - "Journal" of PGH / 4 bound volumes of correspondence, 1931 Jun 1-1935 Jun 1 (Box 9, Folder 119)
      - "Journal" of PGH / Correspondence files - letter from Japanese Consulate, 1933 Jun (Box 10, Folder 120)
      - "Journal" of PGH / Correspondence files - general, 1935 May-1940 (Box 10, Folder 121-142)
      - [incl. leaving Calvary Church (MN) and moving to McCabe Church (Bismarck, ND)], 1941 (Box 11, Folder 143-147)
      - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 148-151)
      - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 152-154)
      - [incl. re. Mother Wolf's death, Jan 14], 1944 (Box 11, Folder 155-157)
      - Correspondence, 1945-1948 (Box 12, Folder 158-173)
      - [incl. re. beginning of Albert Lea pastorate, Jul 10], 1949 (Box 13, Folder 174-177)
      - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box 13, Folder 178-189)
      - [incl. re Elsie Hayes' marriage to Norman Landstrom, Jan 21; Lois Anne Hayes' marriage to Jay Anderson, May 30; Rhoda Hayes' operation for brain tumor, Dec 17], 1953 (Box 14, Folder 190-193)
      - [incl. re. birth of Peter Landstrom, Apr 21], 1954 (Box 14, Folder 194-197)
      - [incl. re. appointment as Superintendent of the Southeastern District of the Minnesota Annual Conference of the Methodist Church, Jun 11], 1955 (Box 14, Folder 198-201)
      - [incl. re. birth of Ruth Landstrom, Nov 7], 1956 (Box 14, Folder 202-205)
      - [incl. re. birth of Cathy Anderson, May 14], 1957 Jan-Jun (Box 14, Folder 206-207)
      - Correspondence, 1957 Jul-1958 (Box 15, Folder 208-213)
      - [incl. re. birth of Lori Anderson, Mar 15], 1959 (Box 15, Folder 214-217)
      - Correspondence, 1960-1961 Jun (Box 15, Folder 218-223)
      - [incl. re. birth of Julie Anderson, Sep 13], 1961 Jul-Dec (Box 16, Folder 224-225)
      - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 226-229)
      - [incl. list of humorous incidents in the ministry of PGH], 1963 (Box 16, Folder 230-233)
      - Correspondence, 1964-241 (Box 16, Folder 234-241)
      - Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 17, Folder 242-257)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 18, Folder 258-273)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1977 Aug (Box 19, Folder 274-287)
      - Correspondence, 1977 Sep-1980 Mar (Box 20, Folder 288-299)
      - Correspondence, 1980 Apr-1982 Jun (Box 21, Folder 300-310)
      - Correspondence, 1982 Jul-1983 (Box 22, Folder 311-321)
      - Correspondence, 1984-1985 Apr (Box 23, Folder 322-330)
      - Correspondence, 1985 May-1986 (Box 24, Folder 331-338)
      - Correspondence incl. invitation to inauguration of President Bill Clinton Vice-President Albert Gore, 1987-1993 (Box 25, Folder 339-345)
  - Correspondence of Elsie Hayes Landstrom
    - Family Correspondence
      - To Paul and Helen Hayes, parents, incl. documentation of trip to China, 1978-1985 (Box 26, Folder 346-358)
      - To Paul and Helen Hayes, parents, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 359-360)
      - To/from Jay Anderson, brother-in-law, 1982 Mar-Apr (Box 27, Folder 361)
      - From Cathy Anderson Sullivan, 1979-1986 (Box 27, Folder 362)
      - From Lori Anderson Stephens, 1978-1987 (Box 27, Folder 363)
      - From Julie Anderson Murray, 1978-1986 (Box 27, Folder 364)
    - General Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous, 1985-1989 (Box 27, Folder 365)
  - Correspondence of Lois Anne Hayes Anderson
    - Family Correspondence
      - To Paul and Helen Hayes, parents, 1980, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 366)
      - To Elsie Hayes Landstrom, sister, 1975-1986 (Box 27, Folder 367-369)
- Biographical Documentation, 1898-1994; Series II
  Material in this series is arranged as follows:
  Subject File of Paul G. Hayes, arranged alphabetically by topic or organization (1898-1994, n.d.)
  Biographical material on Helen Wolf Hayes, chronologically arranged (1920-1988)
  Biographical material on Elsie Hayes Landstrom and Norman Landstrom, chronologically arranged (1980, 1989)
  - Paul G. Hayes
    - Albert Lea (MN) United Methodist Church, 1949-1982 (Box 28, Folder 370-371)
    - Birthday celebrations (99th, 100th,101st), 1989-1991 (Box 28, Folder 372)
    - Bismarck, North Dakota (city of), 1947-1955 (Box 28, Folder 373)
    - Bismarck (ND) High School - Bible Class, 1942-1943, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 374)
    - Boston University School of Theology - Bulletin, 1919-1920 (Box 28, Folder 375)
    - Boston University School of Theology - Diploma, Thesis, Class Papers, 1920 (Box 28, Folder 376)
    - Boston University School of Theology - Miscellaneous, 1916-1921, 1931, 1938-1963, 1978-1982 (Box 28, Folder 377-379)
    - Calvary Methodist Church, 1933-1943, 1960-1961, 1969-1974, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 380-382)
    - Columbia University - Chinese language study - grade report, 1926-1927 (Box 29, Folder 383)
    - Conference Course Study (Methodist Church), 1939-1941 (Box 29, Folder 384)
    - Cost of Living (summaries of travel living expenses), 1934-1935, 1967-1973 (Box 29, Folder 385)
    - Death - Correspondence re. funeral/burial arrangements, 1988, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 386)
    - Death - Last Will and Testament, 1990 Oct 12 (Box 29, Folder 387)